Tyler J. Roberts

(262) 388-4050 | tjroberts314@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyleroberts | https://github.com/tyler314

Summary

Software engineer with 5+ years experience in development and design. My most recent work has been well-balanced between building back-end systems, and front-end web applications. I'm seeking a role where I can leverage the experience I have to be a contributing member to a passionate team, that also requires me to learn new skill sets to succeed.

Experience

Software Engineer

Warner Bros. Discovery · Contract

 $Mar 2023 - Present \cdot Remote$

- I work on the Customer Data Ingestion Team within HBO MAX streaming. Team owns the back-end system that listens for HTTP requests from MAX app users. The system consumes user data, enriches, and stores it.
- Designed and introduced novel integration tests to the application responsible for enriching the data and publishing it to Kafka.
- Added crucial metrics to Grafana for the application responsible for routing the enriched data to the proper downstream consumer.
- General Operational Excellence. Served on-call shifts, performed load tests before big launches, contribute to documentation.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS, Typescript, Node.js, Express.js, Kafka, Grafana, Kubernetes + Docker.

Software Engineer & Project Manager

Copper + Honey Salon \cdot Freelance

Feb 2023 – Present · Remote

- https://www.copperandhoneysalon.com
- I work as the sole Software Engineer on a small business' website. I work directly with the owners to understand their needs, and design software solutions to meet them.
- Created timelines and delivery checkpoints, conducted demos for the owners, and managed all parties involved including an independent UX Designer.
- Leveraged AWS tools such as Cloudfront and AWS Amplify for caching and simple CI/CD, respectively.
- Designed solution for the client so they can easily add and remove employees from the site, seamlessly working across all screen sizes.
- Delivered fully functional website from scratch, and continuing to add new features for the clients.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS, Javascript, React.js, Material UI.

Software Engineer

Amazon.com · Full-Time

Dec 2019 – Jan 2023 · Seattle, WA

- I worked on the Alexa Content Management System (ACMS) used by content creators to author Alexa responses. As well as the Adaptive Response Management System (ARMS), a real time service responsible for filtering and selecting content to be served to our customers, with a tps of over 10k and a maximum latency of 200 ms.
- Lead engineer in delivering adapted responses for Smart Home requests. Such features include sharing insights to customers who make a bad request, listing device capabilities of the requested device, and having Alexa say "Good Morning / Night" when a smart light is turned on or off, depending on time of day.
- Developed a Brief / Verbose Mode for ACMS. This allowed the authoring of responses targeted to customers who have their Alexa devices' brief mode setting turned on, as well as to those who have it turned off. Developed the setting on the front-end, worked with internal 3P teams to read the brief mode setting from Alexa customers and ingested it into ARMS, and developed filtering logic to serve the correct responses based on individual requests.
- Migrated all of Alexa personality content from the old content management system, to ACMS/ARMS. This was a three month endeavor that required the development of bulk migration scripts, working closely with a select few engineers, PMs, and content creators across all supported locales. Had daily standups just for this project.
- Led our org in hiring software development engineers by conducting over 50 interviews in Q1 2022. This allowed our org to get a higher head count for engineers we were allowed to hire. I received our orgs quarterly award for this effort.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS, Kotlin, Javascript, React.js, CI/CD Code Pipelines, Git.

Education

B.S. Computer Engineering, Computer Science, & Mathematics with Physics Certificate (minor). University of Wisconsin - Madison, May 2017